杰森:他就这样撅嘴走了.小坏东西,不领情的……我的儿子走了.
Jason: So he moved pout.That little no good, ungrateful...My son's gone.
我的长子.我名字的缘故,如果我们决定那样做的话.
My first born.My Name's sake, if we decided to go that way.
(倒叙)
(Flashback)
迈克:我想去这个学校.
Mike: I want to go to school here.
麦琪:菲利普 波顿州教师学院.
Maggie: Phillip Boynton State Teachers college.
迈克:是的.
Mike: Exactly.
迈克:米歇尔 西维尔.
Mike: Michael Seaver.
某人:西维尔先生,
Man: Well Mr.Seaver,
你能告诉我们一些你最近的表演经历吗?
would you like to tell us a little about your most recent acting experience?
迈克:啊,就是在昨天我骗了我父母,说我放弃表演.
Mike: Uh, well just yesterday I convinced my parents I'd given up acting.
麦琪:那么你对我们说谎了?
Maggie: So you lied to us?
迈克:啊哈.
Mike: Uh hu.
杰森:那么你从来能有去波顿的打算?
Jason: So you never had any intention of going to Boynton?
迈克:你知道了.
Mike: You got it.
杰森:这有个交易.你需要同样的住房,你需要同样的吃饭,那么你就需要学点什么.你必须是个学生.无论在什么地方学什么.我不管.
Jason: Here's the deal; you want that same rent.You want the Seaver meal plan
Then you've got to study something.You've got to be a student.Study something anywhere
I don't care
迈克:你是说如果我不按照你说的去做,
Mike: So you're saying that if I don't do what you say,
你就让我搬出去?
you're making me move out?
杰森:不是,迈克,你选择搬出去.
Jason: No Mike.You're choosing to move out.
迈克:为什么?
Mike: Why?
杰森:我不知道,你告诉我.我希望你住在这里.
Jason: I don't know.You tell me.I like you living here.
迈克:我也是,爸爸.但是我们在吵什么呢?
Mike: Well me too dad.So what are we fighting about?
杰森:我们不吵了.我要在早上得到你的决定.
Jason: We're not fighting anymore.I want your decision in the morning.
(回到现在)
(Back to present)
麦琪:杰森!杰森!
Maggie: Jason!Jason!
杰森:是的,亲爱的.
Jason: Yeah honey.
麦琪:告诉迈克快点.他的早饭要冷了.
Maggie: Tell Mike to hurry up.His breakfast is getting cold.Come on kids.
过来吧,孩子.吃早饭了.
Breakfast.
杰森:哦,孩子,我怎么告诉麦琪呢?
Jason: (in his head) Oh boy, how am I going to tell Maggie?
瞧瞧它.安然无虑地在她穿着小粉红睡衣.打着鸡蛋.
And look at her.All safe and secure in her little pink robe.Whipping up eggs.
天那!真性感.停下,
God that's sexy.Stop.Stop.Now get back to the problem.
停下.言归正传.我怎么告诉她呢?
How am I going to tell her?
(白日梦1)
(Day dream one)
麦琪:杰森,你在干什么呢?
Maggie: Jason, what are you doing?
杰森:我在抱我的小美人.你不仅仅是漂亮,
Jason: I'm hugging my gal.And it's not just because you're beautiful Maggie.
麦琪.而且我知道你和我可以面对任何事情.甚至迈克搬出去.
It's because together I know you and I can face anything.Even Mike moving out.
麦琪:迈克搬出去了!哦,
Maggie: Mike moved out!Oh you did it didn't you?
你干的,是不是?你用你那些没脑子的废话把我的长子赶出去了.
You with your senseless babbling drove our first born away.
杰森:记住,亲爱的,这里重要的事情是我们的爱情得以挽救了.(麦琪瞪着他)
Jason: Remember honey, the important thing here is that our love will survive.(Maggie shoots him)
杰森:你考虑太多了.她是个成年人.
Jason: (In his head) You are making too much of this.She's an adult.
她会理解的.
She'll understand.
(白日梦2)
(Day dream two)
杰森:麦琪,你最好把打蛋器放下.
Jason: Maggie, you better put down that whip.
麦琪:说什么呢?
Maggie: Pardon me.
杰森:我有坏消息.迈克搬出去了.
Jason: I have some terrible news.Mike has moved out.
麦琪:哦,那很好.
Maggie: Oh, that's nice.
杰森:什么,你不难受?
Jason: What, you're not upset?
麦琪:一点也不.我们可以多生几个小孩.
Maggie: Heck no.We can have more kids.
事实上我现在就想.
In fact I'm in the mood to start trying right now.
(躺在桌子上)
(Lies on table)
杰森:是呀,对.我在做什么?我这就进去咬着子弹挺过去.哦,上帝.子弹.
Jason: (In his head) Yeah right.What am I doing?I'll just go in and bite the bullet.Oh god.Bullet.
麦琪:告诉迈克快到这来,
Maggie: Tell Mike to get here soon,
否则他的三分钟的鸡蛋就煮老了.
or his three minute egg is going to be hard boiled.
杰森:迈克今天早上不吃早饭.
Jason: Well Mike won't be having breakfast this morning.
麦琪:你决定要饿到他屈服为止?
Maggie: You decided to starve him into submission?
杰森:他走了,麦琪.
Jason: He's gone Maggie.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:走了.迈克搬走了.他的车子,
Jason: Gone.Mike moved out.His car, his clothes, everything.
他的衣服,一切.他搬出去去演那愚蠢的戏了.
He moved out to do that stupid play.
麦琪:哦,我不相信.这是他另一个诡计.
Maggie: Oh, I can't believe it.It's just another one of his tricks.
杰森:小甜心,他还拿走了厕纸.
Jason: Sweetheart, he took the toilet paper.
麦琪:我的孩子!但是,
Maggie: My baby!But, but I thought you reason with him.
我以为你说服了他.我以为你解决了一切事情.
I thought you worked everything out.
杰森:我这样做了.我讨厌去说这事.
Jason: So did I.
麦琪,我得怪你.
And I hate to say this Maggie, but I got to blame you.
麦琪:我!等会;你是唯一昨晚跟他谈话的.
Maggie: Me!Wait a minute; you're the one that talked to him last night.
单独,秘密地.而你怪罪于我?
Alone, secretly.And you blame me?
杰森:那是.因为我冷静的说服没起作用,
Jason: That's right.Because when my sober reasoning didn't work,
我就用你那铁石心肠的方法.
I tried your hard as nails approach.
麦琪:什么愚蠢的铁石心肠的方法.
Maggie: What stupid hard as nails approach?
杰森:你知道,
Jason: You know the ultimatum that you didn't have the guts to give him
就是你没有勇气对他进行面对面的最后通牒.
face to face.
麦琪:我不会这样去逼他.在学校或者滚开.
Maggie: I would never corner him like that.Stay in school or get out.
杰森:现在我想我们说为什么.
Jason: Now I think we say why.
麦琪:我相信我的孩子离家出走.我去追他.
Maggie: I can't believe my babies gone.I'm going after him.
杰森:去哪?
Jason: To where?
麦琪:纽约.
Maggie: New York.
杰森:你怎么知道他在纽约?
Jason: How do you know he's in New York?
麦琪:杰森,你知道他在什么城市,
Maggie: Jason, you know what city he's in and you stand there in your
你站在那里穿着睡衣像醉鬼.
robe like Hugh stinking Heffner.
杰森:麦琪,得了.
Jason: Maggie, come on.There's eight million people in that city.
那个城市有八百万人口.我能做什么?
What am I supposed to do?
麦琪:哦,我不知道.
Maggie: Oh I don't know.
我就是担心我的孩子遇到可怕的事情.
I am just worried that my babies fallen into something terrible.
迈克:谢谢你向夜里的孩子提供住宿.
Mike: Thanks for putting me up for the night babe.
女孩:我愿意为你做任何事情,牛仔.
Girl: Any thing for you cowboy.
迈克:我是喜欢演戏的男孩.
Mike: Boy I love acting!
男人:西维尔先生!在每句话之后你必须都说这个吗?
Man: Mr.Seaver!Must you say that after every line?
迈克:她讲了很多好的素材.
Mike: Well she is saying some great stuff.
男人:如果你闭上嘴,她说的更多.
Man: Maybe if you'll shut up, she'll say more.
现在跟那个年轻的姑娘上床去吧.
Now get into that bed with that young woman.
迈克:我是喜欢演戏的男孩.
Mike: Boy I love acting!
麦琪:杰森,我很担心.我甚至没有机会和他说再见.
Maggie: Jason I feel so terrible.I never got the chance to tell him goodbye.
再见,迈克.把你养大成人我很开心.
Bye Mike.It was fun raising you.
杰森:不,不是,麦琪.这是个噩梦.
Jason: No it wasn't Maggie.It was a nightmare.
麦琪:哦.他走了,你很开心?
Maggie: Oh.So you're happy he's gone?
杰森:不开心,麦琪.我难受.我伤心.
Jason: Not happy Maggie.I'm destroyed.I'm hurt.
我很困惑,但是说起来.我爱这个不乖的,
I'm at a loss here, but come on.
不负责任的,自私的,硬心肠的,
I love that no good irresponsible selfish hard headed lofty opportunistic,
高傲的,投机取巧的,危险的,不守规矩的儿子.
dangerous, out law of son.
麦琪:当他说谎的时候是多么聪明呀.
Maggie: He is so cute when he lies.
本:瞧.妈妈,爸爸,
Ben: Look.Mum, dad, I know what you're going to say, but I don't care.
我不知道你们在说些什么,但是我不介意.
This is what all the kids at school are wearing and if you ask me,
学校里的所有孩子都穿这个,如果你们问我,我想这十分酷.
I think it looks darn cool.
杰森:我们遇上大麻烦了,本.迈克离家出走,去纽约了.
Jason: We have bigger problems Ben.Mike has moved out and gone to New York.
麦琪:哦!
Maggie: Oh!
斯丁克: 当我妈妈见到我,她也会哭的.
Stinky: My mother cried too when she saw me.
本:不,斯丁克.
Ben: No Stinky.She's not crying about this.Mike moved to New York.
她不是为此哭的.迈克去了纽约.
We are talking window of opportunity here.
我们正在这讨论机会的切入口.
I have a theory that Mike's old apartment is about to become bens house
我有一个推测,迈克的旧卧室将变成本的游乐室.
of pleasures.
(本的白日梦)
(Ben's daydream)
本:好.姑娘们,排练好了.
Ben: Alright.Enough practice girls.
现在,谁想穿衬衫,谁想什么都不穿?
Now who wants to be shirts and who wants to be skin?
斯丁克:很好.
Stinky: Alright!
杰森:亲爱的,现在得看到好的一面.
Jason: Now honey look on the bright side.
迈克也许会变的富有和成功,而不再需要我们了.
Mike might become rich and successful and never need us again.
麦琪:哦!
Maggie: Oh!
开萝尔:你能相信这点吗?
Carol: Can you believe this?
杰森:开萝尔,难道你不需要乘公交车吗?
Jason: Carol, shouldn't you be catching a bus?
开萝尔:是,我要乘公交车.但是要看我一下.
Carol: Yes I should.But just look at me.
麦琪:现在不行,开萝尔.
Maggie: Not now Carol.
开萝尔:哦,现在不是你女儿打断你们讲话的好时候?
Carol: Oh, is this a bad time for your daughter to have a breakdown?
杰森:是的.迈克去了纽约,我们很难过.
Jason: Yes.Mike has moved to New York and we are pretty upset.
开萝尔:迈克去了纽约!这难道不好吗?
Carol: Mike has moved to New York!Well isn't that nice.
我一个哥伦比亚大学的学生,
Here I am a Columbia student who has to leave at seven am to make a
现在需要早上七点出发去赶十点的课.但是要是我住在纽约呢?
ten o clock class.But do I live in New York?No.
不.我不得不在一个公交站台等待,
I have to wait at a bus stop and get splashed with mud by a traveling
被一个旅行推销员溅了一身泥,
salesman, who then parks his car and offers to wipe me off without using
然后他停好车,不用自己动手擦掉我身上的泥.
his hands.
杰森:开萝尔,你最好换衣服去;要不你上课迟到了.
Jason: Carol, you better change; you are going to be late for class.
麦琪:这样,对于迈克,我们该做些什么?
Maggie: So, what are we going to do about Mike?
杰森:我知道我们不能让步,麦琪.
Jason: Well I know we can't give in Maggie.
我意思是说,我们不能让他住这,成为一个小混混.
I mean we can't just let him live here and be a bum.
我不知道该做点什么.我唯一的希望是他能够理性.
I don't know what to do.Our only hope is that he comes to his senses.
麦琪:这样我们就没有其它希望了.
Maggie: Then we have no hope.
女孩:别留下我,牛仔.别留下我.
Girl: Don't leave me cowboy.Don't leave me.
迈克:对不起,宝贝,我是个居无定所的人,
Mike: Sorry babe, but I'm a traveling man and I gotta go.
我得走.因此,我只有说"唷"!
So I'll just say Yo!
男人:好了.我们需要对结尾部分作些修改.
Man: Ok.We may have to do a little work on this ending.
伙计们,今天就这样了,
People, that's it for today, and please,
请大伙留下你们的地址,我们好给你们修改的剧本.
leave your address so we can send you your revised pages.
迈克:哦,鲍勃,鲍勃,鲍勃.如果你不知道你的地址该怎么办?
Mike: Oh, Bob, Bob, Bob.What do you do if you don't know your address?
鲍勃:到你内衣里面找找.
Bob: Look inside your underwear.
迈克:我意思是说我还没有找到安身之处.你还知道在什么地方能找到每月大概一百或两百块钱的精致干净的房间?
Mike: I mean I haven't found a place yet.
Do you know where I can find a nice clean apartment for say one or two
hundred dollars a month?
鲍勃:好呀.密尔沃基.
Bob: Yeah.Milwaukee.
迈克:莫里斯.听好,
Mike: Maurice.Listen, could you help me out?
能帮个忙吗?我是说我现在能不能拿到我第一次的工资?
I mean is there any way I could get my first days pay now?
男人:米歇尔,在这戏上演之前谁也不会得到薪水,
Man: Michael, nobody gets their pay until the play opens,
还有四个星期呢.
and that's four weeks away.
迈克:四周呀!我怎么活呀?
Mike: Four weeks!How is a guy supposed to live?
男人:你可以卖血.实际上我正要去卖.
Man: Well you could sell your blood.As a matter of fact I'm going right now.
你要去吗?
You want to go?
迈克:不了,谢谢.
Mike: No thanks.
女孩:中心公园南八十五号,小棚屋.
Girl: Eight seven five, central park south.Penthouse.
迈克:哦,莉丝.
Mike: Ah Liz.Listen I was thinking,
听好,我在想,
it would really help me understand my part if I could spend the night
如果今晚我在你的床上睡一觉的话,有助于我理解我的角色.
on your couch tonight.
女孩:对不起.今晚,我男朋友要参加轻重量级冠军比赛.
Girl: Sorry.Tonight my boyfriends fighting for the Light Heavy Weight crown.
凯特:迈克!
Kate: Mike!
迈克:凯特!瞧,我知道我们已经有几个月没见了,但是哎呀,我不在说这些了.
Mike: Kate!Look, I know we haven't seen each other for a few months, but heck, we can't say that anymore.
凯特:你怎么样,迈克?
Kate: How are you Mike?
迈克:很好.凯特,凯特,我做到了!我到纽约了,在一部戏里面担当主角.
Mike: Fine.Kate, Kate, I did it!I moved to New York and I'm starring in a play.
凯特:百老汇?
Kate: Broadway?
迈克:不是百老汇.
Mike: Off Broadway.
凯特:离百老汇多远?
Kate: How far off?
迈克:在二楼的疗养院.没关系.关键是,我在这,你也在这.你看上某个人了吗?
Mike: It's a nursing home on the second floor.It doesn't matter.The point is
here I am and here you are.You seeing anyone
凯特:还没有.
Kate: No.
迈克:我也没有.想住一块吗?
Mike: Me neither.Want to live together?
凯特:迈克.
Kate: Mike.
迈克:好,好.我知道,
Mike: Ok, ok.I know it was my idea for the two of us to be
我们两个只是朋友,这是我的主意;但是,
just friends, but, hey look, the question you got to ask yourself is;
你瞧,有个问题你该问问你自己,你想让这份友谊变的有怎样的意义?
how meaningful do you want this friendship to be?
凯特:我想帮你,但是……
Kate: I would love to help you but...
迈克:嗨,瞧.说实在的.
Mike: hey look.Here's the truth.I just moved away from home.
我刚离家出走.我口袋里面只有一百块钱,而且没地方住.
I've got a hundred bucks in my pocket and no place to live.
只能维持几天,一周,顶多六个月.
It would only be for a couple of days.A week, six months tops.
凯特:我十分想帮你,但是我妈妈到我这里了.
Kate: I would love to help you but my mother's visiting.
妈妈:你好.
Mother: Hello.
迈克:那是你妈妈?
Mike: That's your mother?
妈妈:当然是.
Mother: You bet your but.
迈克:真迷人.
Mike: Charmed.
凯特:见到你真高兴.你不认识这个城市里的其他人?
Kate: It is really nice to see you.Don't you know anybody else in the city?
迈克:我不认识这个城市里的其他人?凯特,
Mike: Don't I know anybody else in the city!Kate, my book is filled.
我的本子都写满了.我就想第一个找你.
I just thought I'd give you first shot.
凯特:谢谢.
Kate: Thanks.
迈克:凯特.以前我们出去的时候,我借钱给你没有?
Mike: Kate.Any of the time we were going out, did I ever lend you money?
凯特:没有.事实上,你欠我五十.
Kate: No.In fact, you owe me fifty.
迈克:你说的对.对不起.
Mike: You're right.I'm sorry.Bad time to bring up money.
现在可不是提钱的好时候.戏上演的时候,我打电话给你.
I'll call you when the play opens.
凯特:我很想看看.
Kate: I would love to see it.
迈克:你现在可以付两张票的钱吗?
Mike: You want to pay for two tickets now?
迈克:奶奶,我是你最爱的孙子.我给你带来了好消息.
Mike: Grandma, it's your favorite grandson.And do I have good news for you.
声音:女士们,先生们.杰瑞 沃尔先生.
Voice: Ladies and gentlemen.Mr.Jerry Vale.
杰瑞:你好,我是杰瑞 沃尔.
Jerry: Hi, I'm Jerry Vale.
迈克:啊,这是我奶奶欧玛和沃利的房子吗?
Mike: Uh, is this my grandma Urma and Wally's apartment?
杰瑞:是的.我是看房人.
Jerry: Yes.I'm house sitting.I do that for all my fans.
我为所有我的崇拜者工作.沃利和欧玛在巴哈马.
Wally and Urma are in the Bahamas.
迈克:巴哈马!
Mike: The Bahamas!
杰瑞:是的,是靠近东海岸的小岛链.
Jerry: Yeah, it's a little chain of islands off the East coast.
迈克:好吧,你瞧,
Mike: well uh, look, Mr.Vale, it's like this.
沃尔先生,情况是这样的.
I am Urma's grandson Mike,
我是欧玛的孙子迈克,我刚搬来纽约来当演员的,
and I just moved to New York to become an actor and I don't have a
但是我没有地方待.你说怎么办?
place to stay.What do you say?
杰瑞:这是个艰苦的时刻,孩子.这会使得你进步的.再见.
Jerry: It's a tough break kid.It will make you a better person.So long.
女服务生:嗨!嗨!嗨!
Waitress: Hey.Hey.Hey!
迈克:请再来一杯咖啡.
Mike: Another cup of coffee please.
女服务生:你在这已经几个小时了.如果你还需要待下去,
Waitress: You've been here for hours.
你需要点吃的.
If you want to stay you got to order some food.
迈克:哦,对不起,
Mike: Uh, well excuse me but that sign in the window clearly offers a
但是橱窗里标语清楚写着提供免费咖啡.
bottomless coffee.
女服务生:还说亲切服务呢.
Waitress: It also says friendly service.
迈克:好吧,太太,
Mike: Look lady, here's the truth.I'm an actor with no place to stay.
告诉你实话吧.我是一个没有地方住的演员.你能帮忙吗?
Would you please cut me a break?
女服务生:你需要帮忙?你告诉你.
Waitress: You want a break?I'll tell you about breaks.
四十年前,
Forty years ago I understudied Mary Martin in South Pacific and that broad
我在南太平洋作为玛丽 马汀的替身,可是那个女人从来不生病.
never even once got sick.
因此我加入了马戏团,
So I joined the circus and spent my reproductive years with w two headed man.
使得我一身与那个长着两个头的男人度过.你想悄悄我孩子的照片吗?
Would you like to see a picture of my kids?
迈克:好呀,我想他们应该很漂亮.
Mike: Uh I'm sure they're beautiful.
女服务生:是呀.出去.
Waitress: Yeah right.Get out.
音乐:每个人都在讲我.我不去听他们讲的任何一个单词.只有我大脑里的回声.人们驻足凝视.
Music: Everybody's talking at me.I cant here a word they say.Only the echoes
of my mind.People stop and stare
迈克:嗨!那是我的车.那是我的全部家当.
Mike: Hey!That's my car.That's all I got.
你知道,如果我缴纳罚金,我就会破产了.
You know if I pay for impound I'll be broke.I got nothing.
我一无所有.你知道问题出在哪吗?是我父亲.
You know whose fault it is?It's my fathers.
男人:给.
Man: Here.
迈克:一块钱.你给我一块钱?
Mike: A buck.You're giving me a buck?
男人:对不起,这是我能够提供的全部了.现在是冬天.
Man: Sorry, it's all I can afford.Its winter.
迈克:会这样.一个无名的无家可归的人给我一块钱.
Mike: It's come to this.An anonymous homeless man gives me a buck.
男人:奥蒂斯.
Man: Otis.
克莉丝:本,你看起来真蠢.
Chrissy: Ben, you look stupid.
本:克莉丝,这是你第一次侮辱我.
Ben: Chrissy, that's the first time you've ever insulted me.
克莉丝:不,这是你第一次在这房间.
Chrissy: No, it's the first time you've ever been in the room.
开萝尔:爸爸呢?
Carol: Where's dad?
本:楼上.
Ben: Upstairs.
开萝尔:爸爸,你下楼来吧.
Carol: Dad, come down here now.
本:我们的领地.出去.女王.
Ben: Our turf.Keep out.The Regents.
开萝尔:我身上被乱画了,本.被这帮穿的跟你一样的十二岁大的孩子.
Carol: I was graffiti-ed Ben.By a gang of twelve dressed just like you.
杰森:开萝尔.
Jason: Carol.
开萝尔:爸爸,我需要和你谈谈.
Carol: Dad, I need to talk to you.
杰森:我不是问你和你哥哥之间的秘密,但是如果你见到迈克,
Jason: I'm not asking you to violate any confidence that you have with
把这钱给他.
your brother, but if you see Mike I want you to give him this money.
不要告诉他这钱哪来的.我希望他吸取教训,
Do not say it's from.
但是我不想他受罪.
I want him to learn a lesson but I do not want him to suffer.
说够多了,现在从我身边走开.
Nough said, now get away from me.
开萝尔:但是爸爸,我有事要说.我下定决心了.
Carol: But dad I have something to say.|I've reached a decision.
本:很明显,女王也下决心了.
Ben: Apparently so have the Regents.
开萝尔:很好.你们都在这.我要跟你们说些事情.
Carol: Oh good.You're here too.I have something to say to you.
麦琪:亲爱的,你的衣服被画的到处都是.
Maggie: Honey, you've got paint all over your coat.
本:你该瞧瞧她的臀部.
Ben: You should read her but.
开萝尔:本,进你房间去.
Carol: Ben, go to your room.
本:开萝尔,你不能指派我去哪.说到底.我不住那个房间了.
Ben: carol, you can't tell me where to go.Anyway.I don't live there anymore.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
本:我昨天搬进车库了.
Ben: I moved up to the garage yesterday.
麦琪:本,在没有允许的情况下,你哪都别想搬.
Maggie: Ben, you don't move anywhere without permission.
本:爸爸说可以.
Ben: Dad said it was ok.
杰森:麦琪,
Jason: Well Maggie, my point was that just incase Mike happened to come back,
是这样,我的想法是如果万一迈克突然回家,
this would symbolically communicate to him that no individual is more
这点就象征性地告诉他,
important or larger than a family as an entity.
没有人比整个家庭更重要或更大.本,
Because as you know, the fiber, the basic familial...
进自己的房间.
Ben, go to your apartment.
开萝尔:我还在这.
Carol: I'm still here.
杰森:怎么回事?
Jason: Why is that?
开萝尔:我怎么样才能引起你们的注意?像本那样穿化纤衣服?
Carol: What do I have to do to get your attention?Wear vinyl like Ben?
麦琪:本穿化纤衣服?
Maggie: Ben's wearing Vinyl?
本:皮的.
Ben: Leather.
开萝尔:我受不了了.这样来回上学等于杀了我.
Carol: I can't take this anymore.This commute is killing me.
杰森:亲爱的,我想家里现在有件重要的事情,
Jason: Honey, I think there's something important going on here,
我们都关注了迈克,而没有注意到你.
and we have been too preoccupied with Mike to even notice it.
开萝尔:终于注意到了,爸爸.
Carol: Finally dad.
杰森:开萝尔要退学.
Jason: Carol's dropping out of school.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
开萝尔:我不会退学.
Carol: I'm not dropping out.
杰森:最终问题解决了.
Jason: Finally that's solved.
开萝尔:听好.如果迈克可以住在城里,,我也可以.
Carol: Listen.If Mike can live in the city, so can I.
麦琪:哦,你不可以,
Maggie: Oh no you don't Carol.You can save your breath.
开萝尔.你少说点.你什么地方都不准搬.
You're not moving anywhere.
开萝尔:我要说的话你们还没有听到.
Carol: You haven't even heard what I have to say.
杰森:那是,麦琪.
Jason: It's true Maggie.
麦琪:不要再说了.
Maggie: Not another word.
开萝尔:什么呀?
Carol: What?
杰森:我想你妈妈说的是现在不是时候.
Jason: I think what your mother's trying to say is maybe this isn't the
right time.
麦琪:我告诉你我要说什么,谢谢.
Maggie: I'll tell you what I'm trying to say, thank you very much.
杰森:亲爱的.我跟她谈谈.好吧.我会处理妥当的.
Jason: Honey I'll talk to her.It's ok.I can take care of things.
麦琪:哦,就像你妥当处理迈克一样?
Maggie: Oh, like you took care of things with Mike?
杰森:哦,你怎么突然责怪起我来了?
Jason: Oh, so now we're blaming me all of a sudden.
麦琪:不,我一直都在责怪你.
Maggie: No, I blamed you all along.
杰森:你得听听事实呀?
Jason: You could hear the truth hu?
麦琪:杰森,我来处理.好吗?好吗?好吗?好吗?很好,我们谈到哪里了?
Maggie: Jason, I am going to handle this.Ok?Ok?Ok?Ok?Alright, where were we?
开萝尔:是这样,我是……
Carol: Well I was.....
麦琪:你什么地方都不能搬.谈话结束.
Maggie: You are not moving anywhere.End of discussion.
开萝尔:你怎么这么自私?
Carol: How can you be so selfish?
麦琪:自私!你认为我把你留下是为了我自己?
Maggie: Selfish!You think I'm keeping you here for me?
开萝尔:绝对.
Carol: Bingo.
麦琪:开萝尔,我让你待在这里我会得到什么?
Maggie: Carol, what would I possibly gain by having you here?
开萝尔:哦,多谢了.
Carol: Oh, thank you very much.
麦琪:亲爱的,我意思实说可能你可能还没有为自己搬出去住准备好.
Maggie: Honey, I just mean that maybe you're not ready to move out on your own.
开萝尔:我怎么没有准备好?你说一件瞧瞧,就一件.
Carol: How am I not ready?Name one thing.Just one.
麦琪:一件.
Maggie: For one.For one.
一件.
If you were adult enough to move out,
如果你足够大搬出去,
you'd be adult enough to know that this is a rotten time to be having
你就足够大知道现在可不是谈论这个狗屁话题的好时间.
this stinking conversation.
开萝尔:我就陷在这里,直到死?
Carol: So I'm trapped here until I die?
麦琪:不,亲爱的.你肯定要比你爸爸和我活的长.
Maggie: No honey, the odds are you'll out live your dad and I.
开萝尔:我觉得迈克做的最棒的事情就是从这里搬走.
Carol: You know the best thing Mike ever did was move away from here.
麦琪:哦,真的?
Maggie: oh really?
开萝尔:是的.至少他有离开你们的好想法.
Carol: Yeah.At least he had the good sense to get away from you.
麦琪:我?
Maggie: Me?
开萝尔:是的.我告诉你们一些其它事情.
Carol: Yeah.I'll tell you something else.
如果我有钱,我也会这么做.
If I had the money, I'd do the same thing.
麦琪:这就是你还住这里的所有原因?
Maggie: Is that all that's keeping you here.
开萝尔:是.
Carol: Yes.
麦琪:这给.
Maggie: Well here.
开萝尔:你干什么呢?
Carol: What are you doing?
麦琪:不要责怪我挡你的道.这是一张空白支票.
Maggie: Far be it for me to stand in you way.A blank check.
你想搬走,搬走.你自由了.
You want to move, move.You're free.
开萝尔:太好了.太好了.我可以今晚就搬出去.
Carol: Great.Great.I can be out by tonight.
麦琪:你搬走吧.
Maggie: You do that.
开萝尔:当然.
Carol: Good.
麦琪:很好.
Maggie: Good.
麦琪:哦!
Maggie: Oh!
克莉丝:妈咪.
Chrissy: Mummy.
麦琪:怎么了,南瓜.
Maggie: Yes pumpkin.
克莉丝:我可以拥有开萝尔的房间吗?
Chrissy: Can I have Carol's room?
迈克:我们明白.我们明白.
Mike: (in his head) let's see.Let's see.
爸爸,我回家的原因是你说的对.原谅我.
Dad, the reason I'm home is because you were right.Forgive me.
(迈克的想象)
(Mike's imagination)
杰森:小混子!小混子!
Jason: Looser!Looser!
迈克:我想跟妈妈谈谈.妈妈,
Mike: I should talk to mum.Mum, your baby boy is home.
你宝贝儿子回家了.现实世界对他来说太艰难了.
The real world was really rough on him.
麦琪:(瞪着他)
Maggie: (shoots him)
迈克:我到底在这里干什么?哦,
Mike: (in his head) What the heck am I doing here?Oh right.
对了.我什么地方都去不了.
I got no where to go.
开萝尔:迈克,你在这里干什么呢?你又脏又恶心.
Carol: Mike, what are you doing here?You look filthy and disgusting.
迈克:啊哈,是的,但是我要是洗个澡就好了.
Mike: Uh, uh, yeah but after I have a shower I will be fine.
开萝尔:帮助我.我在纽约的时候别要去看望我.
Carol: Do me a favor.Don't look me up when I'm in New York.
迈克:我不会.喂,喂,
Mike: I won't.Wai, wai, wait a minute.
等会儿.你说什么意思,当你在纽约的时候?
What do you mean when you're in New York?
开萝尔:这样,我搬那里了.
Carol: Yeah, I'm moving there.
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
开萝尔:哎呀.妈妈给我一张空白支票.
Carol: Uh hu.Mum gave me a blank check.
迈克:等会.在开玩笑,是吗?
Mike: Wait.This is some kind of joke.Right?
开萝尔:不是.有了妈妈的钱,我终于自立了.
Carol: Nope.With mums money I am finally on my own.
迈克:开萝尔,多么令人惊奇的一致呀.
Mike: Carol, what an amazing coincidence.
你在来纽约的路上,
Here you are on your way to New York,
我正从那里回来.为什么不带你一程?
and here I am on my way back there.Why don't I give you a ride?
开萝尔:你愿意?
Carol: You'd do that?
迈克:哦,当然.
Mike: Oh yeah.And Carol,
开萝尔,我而且希望帮助你减少你在曼哈顿最初时期的麻烦.
I also hope to ease your first few troublesome days in Manhattan.
开萝尔:我不信任你.也许我应该尝试不同的破产.
Carol: I don't trust you.Perhaps I should try a different broke.
迈克:破产!开萝尔,我有车.
Mike: A broke!Carol, I've got a car.
杰森:我可以下来吗,或者我又挡你道了?
Jason: May I come down now, or will I just be in the way?
麦琪?:不.
Maggie: No.
杰森:不,我下不来,否则我不得不当你的道?
Jason: No I can't come down, or no I won't be in the way?
亲爱的,如果我挡道,我就待在自己的房间.
Honey, if I am in the way, I'll stay in my room.
麦琪:不是这个意思.是因为开萝尔走了.
Maggie: It's not that.Its just Carol's gone.
我给他一张空白支票,
I gave her a blank check and now she's moving to New York and she'll never
现在她去了纽约,她不会和我说话了.
speak to me again.
杰森:你给了她什么?开萝尔.开萝尔回来.你妈妈不是那个意思.
Jason: You gave her a what?Carol.Carol come back.Your mother didn't mean it.
麦琪:杰森停下.她不会理会的.她恨我们.
Maggie: Jason stop.She doesn't care.She hates us.
杰森:麦琪,所有孩子在某个时期都会恨他们的父母.
Jason: Maggie all kids hate their parents at some time.It's perfectly healthy.
这十分正常.然道你没有恨过你父母?
Didn't you ever hate your parents?
麦琪:没有.他们从不做让我生气的事情.
Maggie: No.They didn't do anything to upset me.
埃迪:你们!嗨,孩子们.
Ed: You hoo!Hey guys.
麦琪:爸爸.哦,
Maggie: Dad.Oh I hate it when they drop in like this.
我恨他们像这样闯进来.一直干扰我的生活.
Always interfering in my life.
埃迪:有什么好消息吗?
Ed: So what's the good word?
麦琪:哦,爸爸,迈克搬去纽约了,开萝尔也去了.
Maggie: Oh daddy, Mike moved to New York and Carol too.
埃迪:你们把我的两个孙儿赶出家门,你们乐意了?你这个庸医.
Ed: Are you happy now that you've driven out two of my grandkids, you quack?
杰森:我没心思跟你埃迪吵.你没来之前,
Jason: I'm in no mood for you Ed.
我们一切都好.
We were doing just fine until you showed up.
麦琪:我们好到极点.
Maggie: Oh the hell we were.
奶奶:哦,我感到紧张.
Grandma: Oh, I sense tension.
本:嗨,伙计们.安静点,我有客人.
Ben: Hey guys.Keep it down, I got some people over.
迈克:两千五百美金要加连字符号吗?
Mike: Is twenty thousand dollars hyphenated?
开萝尔:为什么?
Carol: Why?
迈克:没有为什么.
Mike: No reason.
开萝尔:你在想我的空白支票,是不是?
Carol: You were thinking about my blank cheque, weren't you?
迈克:不是.
迈克:我在想我们的空白支票.
00:22:29,800
Mike: No. Mike :( in his head) I was thinking about our blank cheque.